<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stroke Research | Maëlle Moranges</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/stroke-research/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/stroke-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Stroke Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_7cf38c38523103e5.png</url>
      <title>Stroke Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/stroke-research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI for Stroke Outcome Prediction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/avc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/avc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-postdoctoral-research-at-aistrosight--ai-for-stroke-outcome-prediction&#34;&gt;🧠 Postdoctoral Research at AIstroSight – AI for Stroke Outcome Prediction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-role&#34;&gt;🔬 &lt;strong&gt;Role:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postdoctoral Researcher at Inria AIstroSight, in collaboration with &lt;strong&gt;Hospices Civils de Lyon (HCL)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-funding&#34;&gt;💰 &lt;strong&gt;Funding:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research is conducted within the &lt;strong&gt;AIstroSight team at Inria&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing on the intersection of &lt;strong&gt;AI and neurology&lt;/strong&gt; for stroke patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-scientific-and-technological-objectives&#34;&gt;🎯 &lt;strong&gt;Scientific and Technological Objectives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;early inflammatory response&lt;/strong&gt; after an &lt;strong&gt;acute ischemic stroke (AIS)&lt;/strong&gt; plays a crucial role in patient recovery. This research aims to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify immune system signatures&lt;/strong&gt; in patients experiencing &lt;strong&gt;loss of autonomy&lt;/strong&gt; post-thrombectomy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze gender-based recovery differences&lt;/strong&gt; to improve personalized stroke care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop AI models&lt;/strong&gt; to predict post-stroke outcomes and explore explainability methods to ensure trust in predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-research-approach&#34;&gt;🔍 &lt;strong&gt;Research Approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-statistical--graphical-analysis-for-clinical-interpretation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Statistical &amp;amp; Graphical Analysis for Clinical Interpretation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ Replicated key &lt;strong&gt;statistical and graphical analyses&lt;/strong&gt; from a prior study (originally focused on age) to examine &lt;strong&gt;gender differences in stroke recovery&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
✅ Applied &lt;strong&gt;Subgroup Discovery (SD) on biomarkers&lt;/strong&gt; to identify patient-specific risk intervals.&lt;br&gt;
✅ Developed a &lt;strong&gt;manual interpretation framework with clear thresholds&lt;/strong&gt;, similar to &lt;strong&gt;standard blood test markers&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling physicians to make &lt;strong&gt;quick prognoses&lt;/strong&gt; without requiring computational tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-machine-learning-for-predicting-loss-of-autonomy&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Machine Learning for Predicting Loss of Autonomy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ Expanded the dataset to include &lt;strong&gt;medical history, MRI report descriptions, and additional features&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
✅ Implemented &lt;strong&gt;supervised learning models&lt;/strong&gt; to predict &lt;strong&gt;functional outcomes post-stroke&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
✅ Assessed &lt;strong&gt;explainability techniques&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;SHAP, LIME, counterfactual analysis&lt;/strong&gt;) to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify &lt;strong&gt;gender impact&lt;/strong&gt; in stroke recovery predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate the &lt;strong&gt;consistency of different explanation methods&lt;/strong&gt; for medical decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-clinical-and-computational-collaborations&#34;&gt;🏥 &lt;strong&gt;Clinical and Computational Collaborations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Metchouff&lt;/strong&gt; – Physician at &lt;strong&gt;Hospices Civils de Lyon (HCL)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIstroSight Team, Inria&lt;/strong&gt; – Research group specializing in AI applications in healthcare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-dissemination-and-publications&#34;&gt;📢 &lt;strong&gt;Dissemination and Publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a postdoctoral researcher with the &lt;strong&gt;AIstroSight team at Inria&lt;/strong&gt;, collaborating with &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Metchouff&lt;/strong&gt;, physician at &lt;strong&gt;HCL (Hospices Civils de Lyon)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigate &lt;strong&gt;early inflammatory signatures&lt;/strong&gt; linked to &lt;strong&gt;clinical outcomes&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;acute ischemic stroke (AIS) patients&lt;/strong&gt;. My objective is to &lt;strong&gt;identify immune system signatures&lt;/strong&gt; in patients experiencing &lt;strong&gt;post-thrombectomy autonomy loss&lt;/strong&gt; and to &lt;strong&gt;understand gender-based recovery differences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replicated key &lt;strong&gt;statistical and graphical analyses&lt;/strong&gt; from a related study (originally focused on age), adapting them to &lt;strong&gt;examine gender and clinical evolution&lt;/strong&gt;. This approach was designed to &lt;strong&gt;present results in a format familiar to physicians&lt;/strong&gt;, thereby highlighting the &lt;strong&gt;advantages of AI-driven analysis&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Subgroup Discovery (SD) on biomarkers&lt;/strong&gt; identified population-specific intervals. From these findings, I proposed a &lt;strong&gt;manual interpretation framework with clear thresholds&lt;/strong&gt;, similar to &lt;strong&gt;standard blood test markers&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for &lt;strong&gt;rapid prognoses without computational tools&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel, I am exploring &lt;strong&gt;machine learning on a broader set of features&lt;/strong&gt; (including &lt;strong&gt;medical history, MRI report descriptions, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;) to &lt;strong&gt;predict loss of autonomy&lt;/strong&gt;. I am also evaluating various &lt;strong&gt;explainability methods&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;SHAP, LIME, and counterfactual analysis&lt;/strong&gt;) to study &lt;strong&gt;gender impact in predictions&lt;/strong&gt; and assess the &lt;strong&gt;consistency of different explanations&lt;/strong&gt; obtained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research aims to &lt;strong&gt;bridge AI and clinical neurology&lt;/strong&gt;, offering &lt;strong&gt;more personalized prognostic tools for stroke patients&lt;/strong&gt;. 🚀&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
